<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>something new every day</title>
		<link>//exclav.es/</link>
		<atom:link href="//exclav.es//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Redwoods and tomatoes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I woke up not feeling so great this morning. But it was warm outside, one of those days where you have to go outside. So Alison and I drove over to the East Bay to visit Redwood Regional Park, somewhere that I have previously biked around, but never through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSCF4519.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Redwood 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was good enough to make me feel okay about not doing anything too productive today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DSCF4514.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Redwood 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Processing photos of forests with sun-dappled sunlight is very difficult! I don’t think I’ve ever found a way to make these images look acceptable, let alone close to the beauty of the real life situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, it’s a contrast limitation, and there’s a tradeoff between making an image look HDRy/over-processed, blowing out the nice highlights, and letting the fern-y shadows fall into black oblivion. The above were done with shadow pushing and highlight pulling in Lightroom, and strike approximately what I think the best balance could be. I would be curious to see other photographers’ approaches to this surprisingly difficult lighting challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished uploading the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k4Ec5_DQTnA&quot;&gt;final presentations&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://stupidhackathon.github.io&quot;&gt;2016 San Francisco Stupid Shit No One Needs and Terrible Ideas Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s gotten harder to shift my car into first gear. Now I need to shift into second gear before beging able to push the selector into first almost all of the time. I might try to change the transmission oil sometime in the near future, pending being able to find some jack stands. Internet research seems to suggest that another likely cause of this is misadjustment of some of the shift cables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bought some tomato plants in the afternoon, going to try to fill the Great Dead Spot of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flausenhaus.org&quot;&gt;1611&lt;/a&gt; backyard with them tonight or tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>//exclav.es//2016/05/17/redwoods/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">//exclav.es//2016/05/17/redwoods/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Loquat jam and a bag garden</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What is a loquat? I wondered the same question&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a loquat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6f/Pomological_Watercolor_POM00001040.jpg/1280px-Pomological_Watercolor_POM00001040.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loquat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They taste a bit like a pear, or an apricot, but with less flavor. I guess they’re primarily valued for fruiting about six months offset from most other trees. They also produce &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inkwellhelmets.com&quot; title=&quot;Inkwell Helmets&quot;&gt;Danielle&lt;/a&gt; was kind enough to give me a big bag of loquats, the other day, so I thought I’d try to make jam out of them. I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fullandcontent.com/loquat-jam.html&quot; title=&quot;loquat jam recipe&quot;&gt;this recipe&lt;/a&gt;, which worked out to the following ingredients, in my case:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 cups seeded loquats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2.5 cups sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2.5 cups water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;juice of 1/2 of a lemon (added to cut sweetness)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipe doesn’t use added pectin, as loquats already have plenty. However, this turned out to be way too much sugar! The final jam has an almost candy-like flavor and texture. Oh well, it will be good in yogurt, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_0417.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Loquat jam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing I did today was start a bag garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_0406.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Loquat jam&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glamorous, isn’t it? I chose to go with a bag garden for a few reasons – building planters would be a lot of work, and I’m not sure if I’ll be around longer than the end of the summer, our yard already has grass growing in it, so doing an in ground planting would be difficult, and I have no idea how healthy the soil is around this area. Given that the old Bernal Cut routing for the Southern Pacific train was just a few blocks away from my house, it’s not unlikely that there’s some soil contamination. (To say nothing of lead housepaints, and earthquake-era latrines (which probably have improved the soil quality, honestly.))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://foundsf.org/images/b/bb/SPRR-in-Bernal-Cut-SW-from-Richland-Miguel-overpass-April-5-1922-SFDPW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Southern pacific train&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The precursor to the Caltrain. Not a good spot to grow vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the soil had some really severe mold in it. We scraped off the green stuff (some kind of fruiting body?) and worked the white mycelium back into the rest of the soil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_0390.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Seeds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alison and I planted zucchini, green beans, and Swiss chard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_0403.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Seeds&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s our bag garden! We’ll see whether or not it works. As such a low-effort project, it almost feels like it doesn’t deserve to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_0416.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;The garden&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I don’t know why the zucchini needs to grow in a 12 inch hillocks, but it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<link>//exclav.es//2016/05/16/loquat-bag/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">//exclav.es//2016/05/16/loquat-bag/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
